lynkco.com 2019-10-23

# 

###### 1\. Introduction

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose and delete information relating to you, including your personal data. 

We care about your personal integrity and want you to feel safe when you share your personal data with us. It is important for us to be transparent in how we treat your personal data and provide you with information in an understandable manner.

You are always welcome to contact us if you have any questions or comments. 

###### 2\. Responsibility for your personal data

When we talk about “Lynk & Co”, “we”, “us” or “our” we refer to LYNK & CO International AB (a company registered in Sweden with organizational number 559151-8161). 

Lynk & Co is the controller for the personal data we are collecting and handling which means that we need to comply with certain rules and laws. 

In some cases we may have links to other companies or use their solutions. Such companies process your personal data either in the way we instruct them to (they act as our processor) or in the way they choose themselves (they act as a separate controller). In case the company receiving your information is acting as a separate controller that company’s own privacy policy will apply. 

###### 3\. Personal data collected by us

We collect and use your personal data in different situations and for different reasons, such as if you buy a car, if you start using one of our services or if we get connected in another way. In some cases you need to give us your personal data in order for us to our follow legal obligations or to enable us to enter into an agreement with you. If you do not provide us with such required information we may not be able to offer you our products or services and it is possible that your experience will not be as good. For more information on what we do and why, please see the sections below.

 **3.1 General communication**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To communicate with you and answer questions.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your contact information (email address, telephone number etc), usually your name and other information you give us. Depending on the platform different information is used.   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Legitimate interest. Our legitimate interest is to answer questions and help our customers, users and other persons communicating with us.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for as long as it is necessary for us to handle the questions and in some cases for a longer time to assess legal claims etc. 

**3.2 Contracts**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To prepare and perform our responsibilities according to contracts.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect the information needed for each contract (such as name, national identification number, signatures, company etc.).   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
To prepare and perform our obligations according to our contract.   
**For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for the duration of the contract and in some cases for a longer time to assess legal claims etc. 

**3.3 Legal obligations**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To fulfill our legal obligations.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect the information needed in order for us to fulfill our legal obligations. This can be different depending on which country’s law is applicable etc. For example we need to use information regarding financial transactions (such as name, national identification number, address, amounts etc.) for accounting purposes.   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Legal obligation. Our legitimate interest is to answer questions and help our customers and users.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for as long as it is necessary for us to fulfill our legal obligations and in some cases for a longer time to assess legal claims etc. 

**3.4 Marketing & Events**  
 **3.4.1 Sending newsletters**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To be able to send you information about services, products, special offers, competitions, news and more.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your name, email address, country and IP address.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Your consent (if your are not a customer or user of our products or services).  
Our legitimate interest (if your are a customer or user of our products or services). Our legitimate interest is to inform relevant persons of changes and news.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for as long as it is necessary for us to be able to send you newsletters. If you withdraw your consent to get our newsletter or unsubscribe to the newsletter, we will delete your personal data from our newsletter system

 **3.4.2 Hosting events**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To enable us to host events, campaigns and similar activities (including to invite persons to future events and to evaluate participants' experience of such events).  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your name, age, country of residence, contact details and sometimes picture, film clips and food preferences. We might also gather necessary information in order to book travelling tickets and accommodation.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Legitimate interest. Our legitimate interest is to host awesome events for people and letting the world know about us and the people we hang out with.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as you are interested in receiving information on our events.

 **3.4.3 Publishing photos and videos**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To document and show footage from events etc. to promote and inform people of our activities, products, services etc.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your image in the form of pictures and film clips, and sometimes your voice and name.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Legitimate interest. Our legitimate interest is to inform the public of our activities, products, services etc.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as the material might be used.

 **3.5 Co:lab**  
 **3.5.1 Creating and managing accounts**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To be able to create your personal account in order for you to get access to and post ideas on Co:lab.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your name, email address, phone number, photo, username, display name, country and posted ideas and comments.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
To perform our obligations according to our contract, the [Terms of Use.](https://colab.lynkco.com/lang/en/terms-of-use)  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for as long as you have an account on Co:Lab. You can terminate the account by yourself on the website. If your account is inactive for more than 3 years, we will contact you and ask you if we shall remove your account. 

**3.5.2 Communication**  
**Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
We can send you notifications on activities related to you user account, posts and comments and might contact you if we find an idea you have posted to be interesting to develop further.  
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your name, email address, phone number, photo, username, and display name.  
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
To perform our obligations according to our contract, the Terms of Use.  
**For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data for as long as you have an account on Co:Lab. You can terminate the account by yourself on the website. If your account is inactive for more than 3 years, we will contact you and ask you if we shall remove your account.

 **3.6 urbanX**  
 **3.6.1 Creating and managing accounts**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To be able to create your personal account in order for you to participate in urbanX and start unlocking the city.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your email address.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
To perform our obligations according to our contract, the [ Terms of Use.](https://urbanx.app/terms-of-use)  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
If you terminate your account on urbanX, your personal data will be deleted.

 **3.6.2 Sending notifications (part of the full urbanX experience)**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
Contact you via SMS and email to invite you to secret parties, cool new challenges and information about your rewards as well as general news about Lynk & Co and future Lynk & Co product launches.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your phone number and email address.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Your consent.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
If you terminate your account or revoke your consent to receive invites to secret parties, challenges, rewards and news, we will stop sending you notifications and delete your email address and phone number.

 **3.6.3 Using your location (part of the full urbanX experience)**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To improve your UrbanX experience.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your location using your phone’s GPS-system. The map and location system is provided by Google. To review Google’s privacy policy please click here.   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Your consent. You will not give your consent during the sign-up phase but when you start using UrbanX.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
If you choose not to terminate your account or revoke your consent for us to use your location data, we will stop tracking your location. 

**3.6.4 Sending feedback invitations (part of the full urbanX experience)**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To give you the possibility to provide feedback in order to improve the UrbanX experience.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your email address.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
To perform our obligations according to our contract, the [ Terms of Use.](https://urbanx.app/terms-of-use)  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as you have your UrbanX account and for a shorter period of time if your account is terminated. 

**3.7 Ingroup (previously Co:Mets)**  
 **3.7.1 Managing sign-ups**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
We want to know what people are interested in (customer research). For this we will need to assess and categorize your profile to see if we want to send you surveys and invitations. When you sign-up we will use automated decision to make sure you are above 18 years old and that you consent to our processing. We will also use profiling when assessing your information.  
 **What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect information of your access to car, age, car ownership (incl. new or old), car sharing, thoughts about general sharing, country and city of residence, current school, drivers license, education, email address, employer (Geely or Volvo only), name, gender, income, industry (field of work), citizenship/nationality, student (yes or no), if you live in the city center, suburb etc., children below 18 years old, type of living, year of birth and answers in free text fields.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Explicit consent.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as you are interested in receiving surveys and invitations or if you revoke your consent to be a part of Ingroup. 

**3.7.2 Sending surveys and analyzing the answers**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
We want to know what people are interested in (customer research). For this we will need to send and analyze your answers in surveys.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your answers in the surveys. The information you give may include gender, age, income, input on what you like etc.   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Consent.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as your answers could be used by us for customer research purposes or if you revoke your consent to be a part of Ingroup and having your answers being handled by us. 

**3.7.3 Sending invitations to participate in meetings and focus groups**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
We want to know what people are interested in (customer research). For this we will need to invite you for meetings and focus groups.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We will use your contact information which you gave us when signing up to Ingroup, for instance your email address.   
**What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Consent.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
For as long as you are interested in receiving invitations or if you revoke your consent to be a part of Ingroup.

 **3.8 Recruitment - Applying for a position**  
 **Why do we collect and use your personal data?**  
To evaluate and communicate with job applicants for potential hiring.   
**What types of personal data is used?**  
We collect your name, age, email, contact information, CV and other information you submit.  
 **What legal basis is used for the processing?**  
Legitimate interest. Our legitimate interest is to find people who can start working for us.  
 **For how long do we keep your data?**  
We will use your personal data until the position has been assigned.

###### 4\. Sharing of personal data

We only share your personal data when this is a legal requirement or otherwise permitted by law. In some cases, we use suppliers or other third parties to help us with marketing or our IT systems etc. We also share some information to companies within our company group such as Geely and Lynk & Co in China. In such cases, we have entered into agreements making sure there are measures in place to protect your data.

We try to minimize transfers of personal data to countries outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area.

When we need to transfer your information outside of the European Union and the European Economic Area, we will make sure there are safeguards protecting your data, such as decisions from the European Commission or standard contractual clauses which can be found [here](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32004D0915&from=EN) and [here. ](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN)

If you want more information on how we share your personal data and of possible transfers outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area, please contact us.

###### 5\. Automated decision making and profiling

Profiling is any form of automated processing of your personal data, used for evaluating your personal aspects, in particular to analyze or predict aspects concerning you as an individual.

Automated decision making is the ability to make decisions by technological means without human involvement.   
We will only use your personal data for automated decision making and profiling when you have provided your explicit consent. 

###### 6\. Analytics, cookies and security on our websites

When you visit our websites we use a third-party service (Google Analytics) to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out such things as the number of visitors to the various parts of the websites. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our websites.

If we do collect personal data through our websites, we will tell you and explain how we will use the information. For example we use cookies in a way that is explained in our [Cookie Policy.](https://www.lynkco.com/cookies)

We use firewalls to help maintain the security and performance of our websites. The service checks that traffic to the site is behaving as would be expected. The service will block traffic that is not using the site as expected. To provide this service, website visitors’ IP addresses are used.

The reason why we use analytics, cookies and security measures on our websites is to maintain and monitor the performance of our websites and to constantly look to improve the websites and the services they offer to our visitors and users. The legal basis we rely on to process your personal data is article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR, which allows us to process personal data when its necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests. 

###### 7\. Security

Your personal data is only used when needed and only by the people who need it to provide you with relevant products and services. We always ensure that your personal data is used in a secure way. To prevent unauthorized use or exposure of your personal data, we use appropriate and reasonable physical, technical and organizational security.

When using our websites we encrypt data on our servers as well as provide encryption when data is transferred. If we use suppliers or third parties, access to your data requires secure login.

###### 8\. Your rights

Under data protection law, you have rights we need to make you aware of. The rights available to you depend on our reasons for processing your personal data. You are normally not required to pay any charge for using your rights. We have one month to respond to you, but this time can in some cases be extended with two months if necessary. Besides the right to revoke any consent you might have given us, you have the following rights: 

**8.1 Right to withdraw your consent**  
You can withdraw any consent you have given us at any time. The effect of your withdrawal may lead to you not being able to access all of our services or that your experiences will not be as good. 

**8.2 Right of access**  
You have the right to ask us for copies of your personal data. This right always applies. There are some exemptions, which means you may not always receive all the information we process.   

 **8.3 Right to rectification**  
You have the right to ask us to rectify information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to ask us to complete information you think is incomplete. This right always applies.  

 **8.4 Right to erasure ("right to be forgotten")**  
You have the right to ask us to erase your personal data in certain circumstances.  

 **8.5 Right to restriction of processing**  
You have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances.  

 **8.6 Right to object**  
You have the right to object to processing if we are able to process your personal data because the process is in our legitimate interests.   

 **8.7 Right to data portability**  
This only applies to information you have given us. You have the right to ask that we transfer the information you gave us from one organization to another, or give it to you. The right only applies if we are processing information based on your consent or under, or in talks about entering into a contract and the processing is automated.  

###### 9\. Complaints and Authority

If you think we have processed your personal data incorrectly or if you have any questions or concerns, you can always contact us. If you remain dissatisfied, you can make a complaint about how we use your personal data to the relevant supervisory authority. In Sweden the supervisory authority is The Swedish Data Protection Authority (Sw. Datainspektionen). For more information please see [Datainspektionen.](https://www.datainspektionen.se/)

###### 10\. Contact us

If you have questions about how we use your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer at dpo@lynkco.com.

You can also contact us on the following address:  
Lynk & Co International AB  
Theres Svenssons gata 15  
417 55 Gothenburg, Sweden

Last updated 17th of May 2019
